JAMES "HOLLAND" GRIFFIS

IT MANAGER | Data Analyst

(615) 243-0010

linkedin.com/in/hollandgriffis

hollandgriffis@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

After a successful career in IT Operations/Infrastructure, primarily as a UNIX and Linux system administrator, I transitioned to management. More recently I moved from a people manager role into a position that was a mix of architecture/design and project management. I have wanted to get back to more hands on technical work, but many of the types of work I did previously have moved into the cloud and to more DevOps centric roles. As a result, I am expanding into a new technical area and attending the data analytics bootcamp at NSS. I would like to find a position that will let me use my experience leading highly technical teams, interacting with stakeholders at all levels, and technical skills including my new Data Analytics skills.

SKILLS

Excel | SQL | PowerBI | Tableau | Python | AIX | Linux | Virtualization | HA | Performance Tuning

CERTIFICATIONS

ITIL Foundations Certified

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Certificate Program (in progress)

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN

Bachelor Of Science (BS) Speech CommunicationMiddle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN

DATA EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Apprenticeship

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL| July 2021- January 2022

Six-month, intensive introduction to data analytics and business intelligence processes and tools. Learning includes communicating findings through presentations, storytelling, building reports/ creating dashboards. Tools Learned: Excel, Python, SQL, Tableau, and PowerBI

PROJECTS

- Nashville city cemetery project used city cemetery data with excel to report on vehicular deaths recorded in the Nashville city cemetery sexton logs.
- Lahman Baseball Project Explored MLB stats using SQL to discover unique accomplishments of players and coaches.
- Power BI Created a dashboard showing some of the unique behaviors of squirrels observed in New York's Central Park.
- Tableau Created a dashboard showing world wide infection rates of Covid 19

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BRIDGESTONE, Nashville, TN

A world leader in tire and rubber product manufacturing.

ERP INFRASTRUCTURE ARCHITECT LEAD

2019 - 2021

Led and directed the infrastructure team on a greenfield implementation project for SAP S / 4 HANA Central Finance.

- Researched and led decision-making process to determine cloud or on-premise deployment. Partnered with technical team evaluating global readiness to move infrastructure to cloud.
 - Determined process timeline and how projects were integrated. Set build-out for first phase of S4 implementation on prem with plans to migrate to cloud at a later date.
 - Teamed with EA to ensure build-out met standards; developed hardware and software platform specifics for final deployment.
- Owned and managed the interface between project Agile dev teams and OPS teams to ensure infrastructure buildout completed on time and in budget.
- Supported developers and business teams during sprints for situations like hardware allocation adjustments for HANA data loads.
- Ensured sprints moved smoothly where infrastructure was involved. As dedicated problem solver and facilitator, kept project progressing and avoided / overcame potential delays along the road.

MANAGER UNIX / LINUX SYSTEMS

2015 - 2019

Led Infrastructure Operations team of nine engineers managing and maintaining UNIX (AIX), RHEL, and IBM I Series servers as well as one member in a Devops role supporting Product Development. Managed multimillion-dollar budget to a 2% variance standard.

- Recruited and hired new team members. Facilitated technical and cultural interviews ensuring candidate fit to position and team prior to coming on board. Retained 100% of hires.
- Conducted evaluations and provided performance feedback as an element of required annual cadence and on an ad-hoc basis when problems / opportunities arose.
- Mentored team members to expand and develop areas of interest for skill and career progression. Provided cross-training opportunities to pursue and build new skills.
- Managed vendor relations with companies like Redhat, Suse, and IBM for enterprise
 hardware and software purchases, renewals, and maintenance contracts. Performed annual
 hardware and software audits to right-size company spend and ultimately reduced contract
 expenses most years.

COMDATA, Brentwood, TN

2012 - 2015

A leader in the corporate and fleet payments industry.

MANAGER, DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS UNIX TEAM

Led team of six delivering, managing, maintaining a large, distributed, highly virtualized UNIX / Linux infrastructure, consisting mostly of AIX and RHEL. Managed and maintained vendor relationships and million-dollar budget for the UNIX infrastructure. Compiled and provided metrics and KPI to management.

- Integrally involved with internal and external audit teams to gather required audit data support. Led PCI and SOX audit finding and response team that remediated issues.
- Lead representative to all project planning meetings from concept to implementation. Ensured team members with required skills and abilities and adequate resources were assigned and allocated to each project.
- Mentored staff to troubleshoot and resolve issues at lowest level to conserve time and resources. Developed action plans to escalate complex issues following troubleshooting process chart. Reduced escalation issues and time to resolution by engaged team. Served as a top-level technical escalation point for AIX and Linux issues for team.

2015 - 2021

HCA HEALTHCARE, Nashville, TN

2005 - 2012

The largest private hospital company in the US.

CONSULTING UNIX SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR (SENIOR SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR)

Supported mixed UNIX servers primarily AIX, DG / UX, MPRAS, and Linux. Subject matter expert for Oracle performance on AIX. Supported DBA and middleware teams.

VANDERBILT UNIVERSITY, Nashville, TN

2001 - 2005

University and medical research center.

COMPUTER SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR II

Senior Systems Admin, Center for Structural Biology. Managed purchasing of computational resources, user training, and interfacing with outside vendors. Technology Committee for ACCRE and "Vanderbilt Multi-Processor Integrated Research Engine".